Eagle, say again.
Repeat, please, Eagle.
Zero One Zero, can you confirm deployment?
Roger that, Eagle. Stand by.
Copy that. We got target confirmed.
Eagle is green for go.
Repeat, Eagle is green for go.
Copy that. Deployment in 15 seconds.
Bombardier, give me a confirm
on target Three Zero Niner.
That's Three Zero Niner, confirm.
Copy, Bombardier. OK.
In three... two... one.
Falling.
My worst fear is falling.
Falling like a bomb.
You see, life for me is about distractions.
I try to keep looking up
and forget about what's down.
But when I dream,
I fall.
Left.
Old soldier
Combat soldier
Pick up your weapon and follow me
Follow me to victory
1-0-1
Screaming Eagles
Pick up your weapon and follow me
Follow me to victory
82nd
Airborne soldier
Pick up yourjumpers and follow me
Follow me to victory
Follow me to victory...
Man, you grabbed me. You grabbed me.
You can't do that, man. Well, it's a foul.
I didn't grab you.
Dude, you grabbed me then.
You can't do that.
Man, I didn't grab you.
Why are you lying?
Man, Elwood. Yo, Elwood, man.
He grabbed me, right? You saw it.
I don't know. Maybe.
- See, man, you can't grab like that.
- Fuck you, man.
- Fucking holding...
- You wanna try it again, motherfucker?
Let's go, baby.
Hey, Video, throw me the goddamn ball.
OK, but I'm quarterback. Can I be?
- Come on. Come on.
- All right. Let's see what they got.
Hey, yo, can I play?
Whoa, Parsons, got something for me there?
- You put it in the battery?
- Yeah, no problem.
Hey, can I play?
I was champion wide receiver at high school.
I can catch that ball, man.
- You're so fucked up, you couldn't catch a bus.
- Don't be such a pussy and let him play.
Come on. Get down. Get down.
On "hutt". Down.
Come on. Come on.
- Gimme some action.
- Hutt.
These were my guys.
Fighting the dull fight.
Soldiers with nothing to kill except time.
They know that war is hell,
but peace...
peace is fucking boring.
Give me back the motherfucking ball.
Er, guys.
Guys.
Guys!
What?
Er, just letting you know.
Parsons is dead.
Parsons McCovey
was a casualty of war.
The only difference was that this was
the Cold War and he was a fucked-up junkie.
There'd be no hero's burial for Parsons.
I regret the death of your son immensely.
There was nobody in the battalion
I would have trusted more with my life.
In him were resplendent
the virtues of honour and loyalty
to his country and God,
that keep our civilisation together.
He fell off the rooftop
while making technical repairs
to the antennae that guard against the enemy.
Technical repairs? Where did that come from?
I tried to think
what McCovey might be doing up there.
OK, go on.
He died, though not in combat,
in the line of duty,
and he had his country uppermost in his mind.
My deepest regrets, Colonel Wallace Berman,
US Army, Commanding.
You kept this one short.
I thought it might be better
not to get lost in detail, sir.
I like the touch about me
trusting him with my life.
It's a new angle, sir.
Here's something, though.
The word "resplendent".
That's not a good word to describe a soldier.
We'd better come up with something else there.
What about "contained"? In him
were contained the virtues of honour and loyalty.
- That's much better.
- Oh, much better, sir.
Don't let the word "resplendent" leave this base.
Yes, sir.
OK. What is this? What have we here?
Just some requisitions, sir.
1,000 gallons of Mop & Glo.
My God. Do we really need that much?
Cleanliness is next to godliness.
Herman the German. How goes it?
How do you do, mein Freund? How are you?
Doing just fine. Just fine.
Shall we do business today?
Sure thing. Guys.
I think you'll be pleased.
That's beautiful.
Look at the sparkle.
That's real cleaning power.
Sehr gut Sheiße, ja?
Sehr gut Sheiße, mein Freund.
US Army's finest. 500 gallons ready to go.
Three things I love about Germany:
My Mercedes-Benz:
No speed limit on the autobahn:
And a black market
for anything I can get my hands on.
Fight The Power
The number, another summer
Sound of the funky drummer
Music hittin' your heart
cos I know you got soul
Brothers and sisters
Listen if you're missing y'all
Swingin' while I'm singin'
Givin' what you're gettin',
knowin' what I know
While the Black bands sweatin'
And the rhythm rhymes rollin'
Got to give us what we want
Gotta give us what we need
Our freedom of speech is freedom or death
We gotta fight the powers that be
Let me hear you say
Fight the power
Fight the power...
Hey, Elwood, what's up?
Outstanding, Hicks. How you doing?
So...?
You don't look so good, Hicks.
- You got anything?
- Depends on what you want.
Er, it's... horse.
Can't help you.
You know, fuck, Elwood.
I outrank you, man, so don't give me any... crap.
I appreciate that, but I can't help you.
Look, man, I don't do retail. I only cook the shit.
Why don't you go see Sergeant Saad?
There's basically
two types of guys in the army -
the motherfuckers and the motherfucked.
Sergeant Saad is the third kind.
He fucks the motherfuckers.
Which is doable
when you're the chief MP by day
and the director of retail heroin sales by night.
Something that makes my life simple.
I just cook high-grade Turkish morphine
into smack and wholesale it straight to him.
Everyone's happy.
So, how much we get?
Well, after we give the Turk back his share,
we got er... nine grams.
Nine grams? Six hours of cooking
and all we get is nine grams?
You wanna tell the Turk
you're not happy, be my guest.
Bullshit. We're the ones doing all the work,
taking all the risks,
and Saad's making all the profit.
Garcia, I just need you to do your job.
Can you watch those thermometers
and keep your mouth eating those hotdogs?
Heroin, cocaine, marijuana,
lysergic acid, diethyl... Whatever the hell it is.
Amphetamines, traces of barbiturates,
estrogen...
Estrogen?
McCovey was on the pill?
How could this be possible?
- Well, he might have taken it by mistake, sir.
- What?
The pill. He might have thought
it was something else.
Fine, but he didn't take heroin,
speed and cocaine by mistake, did he?
It seems unlikely, sir.
This isn't good, Elwood,
drugs on a base like this.
Did you know anything about this?
How could someone get drugs in?
I really don't know, sir.
I always try to keep away
from people like McCovey.
Elwood, we've got to try to clear this matter up,
goddamn it.
I cannot... Scratch that.
I will not have this kind of thing
going on at my base.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
My officer evaluation report goes
in front of General Lancaster in three weeks.
If I don't get that goddamn star, I'm finished.
- Sir, you've got to relax...
- Don't you tell me to relax!
You're an E4. I'm a goddamn full-bird colonel.
You don't talk to me like that.
- You understand me, soldier?
- Yes, sir.
Oh, Jesus, Elwood, I'm...
I didn't mean to take it out on you.
Elwood, I'm... I'm sorry.
It's OK, sir. I understand
the kind of pressure you're under.
This isn't mine.
I don't know anything about it.
And there's no smoking in here.
I need someone to sign here. It says Berman.
You're Berman?
I'm Colonel Berman, all right, but I don't know
anything about any goddamn chair.
- I'm telling you, son, it's not mine.
- It is yours.
- Oh, Liz. Hello, darling.
- Isn't it beautiful? It's for you.
It's for me?
I got it for under 30.
They didn't know what they had.
- 30 thousand?
- I couldn't believe it was so cheap.
- Dollars or Deutschmarks?
- What do you think, Elwood?
Well, can you sit on it, ma'am?
Of course you can't sit on it. It's an antique.
Oh, well, it's very nice.
Darling,
can I borrow Elwood for a few hours?
There's some things I need him to do.
God.
Wait. Almost. Almost.
...under the deal signed exactly a year ago
in Stockholm to build East-West trust,
and reduce the risk of war.
East and West have always feared
that such an enormous exercise
might be used as a cover for a build-up for war.
You didn't make it yet?
Sorry. You angry?
No.
Ray, honey. I need you to do me a favour.
The Colonel's giving a party
and I need you to find out about decorations.
- What's he want a party for?
- He wants to impress the General.
His position's under review
and I thought a party would help.
Will you?
Hm?
Oh, you mean a party party?
Like for everyone's fun.
Oh.
...are procedures
to ensure no cheating in future.
And all sides agree this first onside verification
of conventional forces
is a major step forward
in building new trust and confidence.
Can you switch that off?
Just turn that engine off, come on over here.
- Is there a problem?
- Where are you taking this Hummer?
We have orders from Colonel Berman.
OK. Who are you?
Specialist Ray Elwood.
What's this?
We have orders
to pick up party decorations in Mannheim.
Party decorations?
Yes, First Sergeant.
Colonel's having a party.
Sounds like a pretty dangerous mission.
No disrespect intended,
but may I ask who you are?
Yeah, you can ask.
I'm your new Top. First Sergeant Robert E Lee.
Well, pleased to meet you, Top.
Welcome to the 3-17th.
Thanks, Specialist.
- I didn't know we were getting a new Top.
- Why would you?
I'm Battalion Clerk here.
I usually do paperwork on all the transfers.
OK, thanks, guys. I'm sorry to keep you.
No problem.
Hold it for a second there.
You got the time, son?
Oh, yeah, it's almost ten.
That's a nice watch. Show me that.
Where did you get that?
My father gave it to me.
Your father gave it to you?
He must be quite a guy. What's he do?
He's a barber.
Barber?
Gee, he must cut a lot of hair.
Yeah.
OK, better be going, then.
Don't wanna be late
picking up them party decorations.
Let's go.
Bear Witness
Bravo Two Zero.
Bravo Two Zero, come in.
Bravo Two Zero. Bravo Two Zero, come in.
Shit! Turn that down, man.
Turn down the fucking music, man.
Bravo Two Zero, please respond.
What's going on, Hicks?
Er... Bravo Two Zero here.
Bravo Two Zero, commence tactical
manoeuvre area Two Niner Alpha Romeo.
Take position on phase line
Foxtrot Delta Four Seven.
Fuck.
What the hell's Two Nine Alpha Romeo?
I got a very weird vibe from that guy.
I personally didn't like him.
- He's our new Top. What do you expect?
- What was that shit about the Rolex, man?
He could know about the operation,
he could know something.
Jesus Christ, don't get fucking paranoid, Garcia.
Just be cool.
I'm cool.
- Fuck, man. I can be cool.
- Good. That's why I'm telling you.
Figured out where we're going yet, man?
Er, no. We're going the wrong way.
Shit, er... Hey, Johnnie,
make a... a left.
I told you to make a left across that field.
I did, man. I went left.
Ich Bin Ein Arschloch
What was that bump?
Oh, shit, man.
We just ran over a car, man.
We just squashed a car.
What kind of car?
A Volkswagen. A fucking Beetle.
Oh, no.
We squashed a Beetle.
Look out, man.
Stop.
Stop!
What's going on?
What the hell are you doing here?
- Whoa!
- Stop!
Stop.
- These dudes are freaking me out.
- I don't like 'em, either.
Hey, Johnnie, why don't you just
get us away from these fuckers?
What the fuck is he doing?
Holy shit! What the fuck was that?
What's wrong with these monitors?
They've gone all orange.
Johnnie, I thought I told you
to get us out of here.
That's our fucking unit.
Just up ahead.
Is that you back there, Bravo Two Zero?
Did you complete
your Two Niner Alpha Romeo?
Er... We er... completed that.
OK, good work, guys. Get in formation.
Holy shit!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
These guys are dead.
Garcia, get in that truck and follow me.
What?
- Hey, what's in the trucks?
- I don't know. Let's find out.
- Hey, no way, man.
- Just get in the fucking truck.
All right.
Uh-oh.
Jackpot.
Oh, shit. Holy shit!
Grenade launchers.
MAG guns, stinger missiles.
Jesus Christ, this is worth millions.
3 million maybe.
- Maybe $5 million.
- It's all brand-new.
We gotta take this back.
This stuff gets us nothing but heavy jail time.
- We're not taking this back.
- It's big time. We can retire on this.
I agree 100%/.
This is way out of our league.
They kill you for stuff like this.
This is very serious shit.
- There's no time like now. If we pull this off...
- There's no time like now? Are you crazy?
We're not weapons dealers.
Would you kindly shut up?
Man, you're so negative. I'm trying to think.
Hey.
We're smart, right?
Yeah.
Now, we could do this.
- We could do this.
- Oh, man.
What do we do with this shit?
Well, first we need to store it.
And I know the perfect place.
Hey, this place gives me the creeps.
Yeah, it's supposed to.
- Hey, friend, what's up?
- Hey, Elwood.
What's going on, man?
Nothing much. I got some stuff I need to store.
Can you help me out?
Sure thing, man.
Hey, are we gonna party afterwards?
Does the Pope shit in the woods?
Hey, we can do a lot of things
with the cash we make off this.
You know what I'm saying?
Cos I was thinking about opening up a bar,
a nice, classy place.
Me and you'd be partners.
What do you think?
Sure.
Why not?
Fuck!
This one ready to go?
Yeah, almost. Almost.
Easy.
You be all right?
Yeah.
- You ain't out in 30, I'm coming in.
- Don't worry, I'll be fine.
Turkish music
- Elwood, how are you, my friend?
- Hey, Davood, how are you?
- Are you hungry? You want something to eat?
- Oh, no, I'm fine, thanks. I'd better get up.
Say hi to your sister, all right?
A lot of guns.
Where did you get all this stuff?
Santa Claus.
Santa Claus. That's funny.
He came down the chimney
and put it under the tree, hm?
Yup.
So...
...how about this?
I give you 20 kilos on top of my next shipment,
and you cook that
along with my share of the shipment,
and you make a lot of money.
- 20 kilos?
- Mm.
No. I want cash.
25.
Look, I know somebody else
who's very interested in this merchandise.
OK.
Maybe they'll pay you cash.
35.
29.
I hate to break that 30 mark.
It's a religious thing with me.
I'm afraid you'll have to,
cos 30 kilos is my final offer.
He's sending us 30Ks. One week.
30Ks?
Holy shit! That's, er...
- A lot.
- Well, how do we cook that much?
- It'll take us, like, a year.
- It's gonna be cool.
French Foreign Minister Dumas
yesterday expressed discomfort...
...has welcomed East German reforms
with such open arms.
Politically, Mr Gorbachev
has never been more vulnerable.
This is really impressive.
Hey, guys, careful with my shit.
You're pretty well equipped for a Spec Four.
I got receipts for everything.
I'm sure you do.
Hey, Top, look at this.
Check and see if there's anything inside.
Nothing.
Hm? Mm-hm.
I'll bet this don't come cheap.
This ain't exactly regulation stuff here,
is it, soldier?
I don't really know.
No, I guess not.
Look, I'm gonna come round here tomorrow.
I want this place looking like a regular quarters.
You follow?
Look, I know it ain't exactly regulation,
but the last Top didn't seem to mind.
Well, him and me are a bit different.
Look, Top,
is there a way you and I could talk in private?
These guys kinda make me nervous.
Does it really have to play this way, Top?
How do you suggest we play it?
Well, what is it you want?
I mean, you and me, I think we...
I think we got a lot in common.
Barriers are coming down in Hungary.
So must they fall
throughout all of Eastern Europe.
For example, I see you're an admirer
of Japanese technology.
No problem.
The TV's yours.
What I'm trying to say is,
what's it gonna take
for you and me to make nice?
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
The world has waited...
There's your answer.
Elwood.
Hey, this'll take a second.
- I'll meet you down there.
- All right.
Where are you off to in such a hurry?
Nowhere, really.
Just had a couple of things to do.
You're always off with your buddies.
I never see you any more.
It's just cos I've been really busy.
- Busy?
- Yeah.
- It's the guest list.
- Guest list?
Party. Are you still helping me?
Oh, the par... Yeah. Sure. Definitely.
We found out the Colonel's related
to the Iron Boar.
- The Iron what?
- The Iron Boar, as in male pig.
I had a lawyer trace his family tree,
and he's a distant relative
of a Civil War hero, John Bell Hood.
They called him the Iron Boar.
He'll announce it to General Lancaster
at the party, to help his promotion.
Sergeant Lee's daughter.
That's Top's daughter? You're kidding.
See something you like, Elwood?
Nice dive.
Thanks.
The new Top, what do you think he's up to?
He's a washed-up vet
who wants to throw his weight around.
But right now he's on your case, my man.
Yeah, well.
Hey, check out this girl.
- Why?
- That's Top's daughter.
No shit.
You know what I'm thinking?
You could be thinking almost anything.
- Maybe I should ask her out.
- You're fucking crazy, you know that?
Imagine how much that'll fuck with his head.
It's perfect.
Hey.
- So, have you got a problem with your car?
- Yeah. It won't start.
It might be the battery. Want me to look?
Hey, you're Robyn Lee, right?
Yeah. How d'you know that?
I'm Battalion Clerk here for the First Battalion.
I kinda know everything.
Hm, must be handy.
Hey, you're a good diver.
I saw you in there at the pool,
diving off the high platform. How do you do that?
What do you mean? Are you scared of heights?
Let's just say you wouldn't get me up there.
You should try it.
It's fun.
Fun? Why is it fun?
Falling through air. It's kinda cool.
You're kidding me. You like falling?
Sure. Why not?
Hey, I think I found the culprit.
You wanna give that a try?
- What a guy!
- That's me.
Actually, I'm Ray Elwood.
Everyone calls me Elwood.
- Thanks for fixing my car, Elwood.
- Yeah. No problem.
You wanna go out Friday night?
It's a vineyard I visited last summer,
just a small one in the Napa Valley.
Pinot grapes.
It's for sale.
- You thinking of buying it, sir?
- Well, I wish.
No. But I have a pretty decent collection
back home,
and I've always wondered what it would be like
to make my own wine.
I could just about afford it.
Of course it's unrealistic.
Have you heard about those two missing trucks?
- What trucks, sir?
- During Reforger two trucks went missing.
The drivers were killed in an accident with a tank
at some gas station out near Karlsruhe.
They found the bodies,
but they can't find the trucks.
How odd.
- You wanna hear the best part?
- What's that, sir?
It's Colonel Marshall's infantry,
so he's taking the heat.
Great news, sir.
Elwood, could I tell you a little secret?
Of course, sir.
Have you heard
of the Civil War General John Bell Hood?
The Iron Boar?
You know of him?
- Everybody knows the Iron Boar.
- I didn't know he was so well known.
- Mm.
- It turns out that I am an actual relative.
A relative of the Iron Boar? Awesome.
I want you to keep it under your hat.
I'm gonna surprise the General at the party.
Excuse me.
Private First Class Brian Knoll
reporting for duty, sir.
I'm not an officer, so you can cut the "sir" crap.
- Sorry.
- What do you want?
I just arrived. The orderly sent me down here.
Oh, great. Is that your 201 file?
Yes, sir. Er... yes.
You can sit down if you want.
So, how come they assigned you here?
I put in for it.
My fiancée is here on base,
so we arranged to transfer together.
Ah, how sweet.
Who is she?
Margolis, Carol Ann, Private First Class.
You call her by her last name?
What do you do, salute in bed?
It says here they put you in 5-19.
Yeah.
That's my room.
Didn't... Didn't Sergeant Lee tell you?
We're gonna be roommates.
So while Carol Ann's been here for six months,
I'm stuck in San Antonio,
just pulling whatever strings I could,
kissing the Base Commander's ass
like you would not believe, not literally, but...
Boy, oh, boy. I mean, so check this out.
- So then...
- Jesus Christ, shut the fuck up.
I guess I don't really give a shit.
You're only here cos Sergeant
fucking dickhead Lee's on my case.
Until I get that shit straightened out, I don't
wanna hear about your girlfriend, or anything.
You roger that?
Anderson underwent his rookie season
at Milwaukee as a starting quarterback...
Hiya, Top. How's it going?
- Daddy, this is Ray Elwood.
- Oh, yeah, we already met.
I'm going out. I won't be home till late.
How the hell can you afford this car?
Oh, I got a great deal.
Mercs are a lot cheaper in Germany.
I don't believe it.
What?
Your dad. He's following us.
I don't believe it.
Hey, how's it going?
- Hey, Elwood.
- Looking good.
Hey!
Alle schon da.
Tut mir Leid.
Mit diesen Schuhen können Sie nicht rein.
Blue Monday
What's going on with you and my dad?
What do you mean?
There's something going on.
I'm the natural enemy of guys like your dad,
mostly cos I don't give a shit about the army.
If you don't give a shit, why did you join?
I didn't exactly have much of a say in the matter.
I got caught stealing a car
and the judge gave me a choice -
six months in prison or three years in the army.
- I made the mistake of choosing the army.
- I get it.
My dad has a problem with guys like you.
So you're out with me to piss him off?
No. I, er...
That's it, isn't it?
Yeah, that's...
I'm fucked up. I'm really sorry.
Yeah, that's definitely fucked up.
I'll take you home.
I didn't mean to get you into this.
Are you seriously out with me
just to piss off my dad?
Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
Are you crazy?
He's the First Sergeant of your company.
He's not somebody you wanna piss off.
You realise, he's gonna cut your balls off.
Yeah, probably.
So, what if I stay?
There's a chance you're gonna lose your balls.
Do you think I'm worth it?
Yeah. Sure. Why not?
Fine.
Do you want one of these?
- What is that?
- Ecstacy.
How does it feel
To treat me like you do?
When you've laid your hands upon me
And told me who you are
I thought I was mistaken
I thought I heard your words
Tell me, how do I feel?
Tell me now, how do I feel?
Those who came before me
Lived through their vocations
I've got something I wanna show you.
What is it?
A burn.
How did it happen?
When I was a kid, my dad was drunk
and he dropped a cigarette on my nightgown
and it caught fire.
It was an accident.
It's really ugly, isn't it?
Get up! Get up! Get up!
At the armoury. Full gear. Five minutes!
Five minutes?
Count 'em.
- Elwood, what the hell are we doing?
- Target practice.
Elwood, hand me your rifle.
I want you to pack the M-60.
I'm not qualified to operate it.
There's a time and a place.
You're gonna learn in the heat of battle.
Hand it to him.
The 60's a heavy mother.
So am I.
What's the matter, Elwood?
Your fitness lacking?
You wanna do the confidence course
a few times to get you back into shape?
No, thanks, Top. I'll be fine.
I direct your attention to that spot over there
that has been marked with an X.
We have here the prototype
of a new Russian tank.
We are here to test the vulnerability of said tank
to sustain fire from an infantry platoon.
Squad...
Lock and load one magazine.
Take up a good firing position.
You will fire on my command.
Sustain fire until the order
to cease fire's been given.
Ready?
Fire!
So, you did Top's daughter?
Think I may have a problem.
No shit.
I like her.
I really like her, you know.
I mean, she's different, man. She's cool.
There's this... I just fucking dig her, you know.
That's a problem.
Yeah.
Elwood.
Heard you lost your ride, baby.
I was getting bored with that car.
You'd better take note there, Stoney.
It ain't too healthy hanging around this guy.
Look at the shit he's making you eat.
Oh, you want some meatloaf, Saad?
That's a fucking insult to me.
I don't eat meat.
Human beings don't have the proper teeth
and can't digest that shit.
It stays in your guts for three weeks
and it rots.
That's your problem. You ain't got no discipline.
- Are you trying to make some point here, Saad?
- Yeah.
The cabinet in the storage room
was empty, man.
What do you mean, it was empty?
Empty. It means nothing was in it.
I paid my hard earned for thin fucking air.
You looked inside the battery, right?
Like always. Except this time nothing was in it.
What the fuck is that?
You trying to pick a fight with me, Elwood?
Is that what you really wanna do?
I sent Parsons there to stash it.
Stupid fucking junkie
probably did something with it.
Parsons ain't around.
Ain't that real fucking convenient?
Hey, relax, man. It's already sorted.
I got a brand-new batch ready for you.
Maintenance area at the swimming pool,
usual place.
I put it there myself. It's definitely there, OK?
It fucking better be.
You understand me?
Do you understand me?
This meatloaf looks great, doesn't it?
In the article... In the article there was a photo
of a Confederate General John Bell Hood,
affectio... affectio... affec...
affectionately known as the Iron Boar.
Known as the Iron Boar.
- The Iron Boar.
- Who are you talking to?
No-one. How are things going downstairs?
- Are you ready? Guests will be here soon.
- I'm coming.
I was reading a copy of The Modern Soldier,
and there was an article
on the guerrilla fighters in the Civil War.
There was a photo of the Confederate General
John Bell Hood, affectionately...
affec... affectionately known as the Iron Boar.
The Iron what?
Boar. B-O-A-R. As in male pig.
It was Liz who actually noticed it,
but the resemblance to myself
was absolutely uncanny.
So we commissioned a lawyer
to begin tracking down court records,
passenger ship lists, that sort of thing,
and it was finally confirmed just last week
via what is known round here
as the Lynchburg Convergence,
where a certain Trevor Berman and a hood girl
known as Ethel, wed and had two boys
in the town of Lynchburg, Virginia.
One of those boys, Gary Berman,
is my great-great-uncle.
A descendent of the wild boar.
Sir, that's the Iron Boar.
I guess I'm surrounded
by people with famous relatives.
Isn't that so, Marshall?
I try not to play it up,
but when I found out I was related to former
Army Chief of Staff General George C Marshall,
I guess it gave me
a strong sense of my heritage.
I've always been proud of my family,
but knowing that I was from fighting stock...
...affected me quite profoundly.
I seem to recall this General Hood.
He was involved in some disastrous battle
and lost a leg, didn't he?
I wouldn't say it was disastrous.
And an arm.
- He lost an arm as well, didn't he?
- No, he didn't lose an arm.
He lost the use of it. He kept the actual arm.
- Drink, General?
- Thank you.
Mrs Colonel.
You know what?
I don't go much for this lineage shit.
I'm not related to anyone famous and
this family line bullshit makes me feel insecure.
My belief is, if you come from dirt,
you fight better
because you don't wanna go back to the dirt.
The best fighters in the world
are people with nothing to lose.
Get me another one of these, will you?
Right away, sir.
- How's it going?
- Oh, the usual.
Berman and Marshall
trying to suck the General's dick.
What's he doing here?
I don't know.
It's supposed to be a party
for officers only.
Damn.
The General's sure happy to see his ass.
How's it going?
What you doing walking around here,
white boy? You crazy or something?
I'm just trying to get back to my room.
You know, I don't want any trouble, or...
No trouble?
OK.
You're with Elwood now, ain't you?
You Elwood's homey?
Yeah, he's my roommate.
Oh, you're roommates?
That's real nice, man.
Er, Scotch on the rocks
and a Coca-Cola, please.
Didn't expect to see you here.
Yeah, well... here I am.
There you go.
Jesus Christ, look how they got you dressed up.
Ain't you sick of being fucked by a white man?
You and me can step outside right now.
Whoa!
You think you can take me?
Uh-oh, customers.
Yeah, maybe.
Straight up, hand to hand, you got a shot.
Maybe.
But maybe I wear a blade.
Maybe I got a.45 cocked and locked
to shove up your ass.
You ain't considered that, have you?
Hey, you wanna know something?
You ain't like Elwood here. You got guts.
Guys like you get all the medals.
Hey, Bob. Get your ass over here.
There's someone I want you to meet.
Excuse me.
He murdered your car?
Yeah, shot to pieces.
The entire unit used it for target practice.
Even me.
Why would he do that?
That's pretty extreme, even for him.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Is there something going on I don't know about?
What do you mean?
Are you into some kind of shit on the side?
I've lived on base my whole life.
I know what goes on.
I also know my dad
doesn't take a disliking to just anyone.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
You're into something.
Aren't you?
A fiasco.
- A debacle even, wouldn't you say?
- Goddamn it, it was your idea.
- I'd never heard of the fucking Iron Boar.
- Do something, then.
Marshall's gonna take that promotion
if you don't.
Take the initiative, for God's sake.
You're a soldier. Go on the attack.
- I've got an idea.
- What?
- Leave it to me. Don't worry about it.
- Tell me. Tell me.
You have a serious problem.
My dad's a pretty heavy guy.
He'll really fuck you up.
When you say fuck me up, what do you mean?
I mean, fuck you right up.
He's done three tours of Vietnam.
He's killed a lot of people.
- Whoa. Are you saying he's gonna kill me?
- I don't know, but...
He's not a guy to mess with.
Why are you telling me all this?
I guess I don't want him to fuck you up.
You realise that's probably the nicest thing
anyone's said to me in my whole life?
I love this guy, don't you?
General?
There's something
I'd like to talk to you about.
Yes.
What do you think about the idea
of a training exercise?
Er, what do you have in mind?
Well, with all this activity in the East,
I thought we should stay on our toes.
Maybe I could put a company of my men
up against Marshall's, see how they'd go.
Do you really think
you're up for this sort of thing?
Oh, yes, sir. It could be
a straight defensive/offensive exercise.
Maybe the nuclear facility.
I could put my men on a full alert.
See how they'd hold up against an attack.
You want to defend the nuke base
against Marshall's infantry?
Yes, sir.
- Wallace, can I see you in the kitchen?
- Just a moment, honey.
Er, Marshall, what do you think?
Er... sounds good to me.
Excellent.
I think I know what your problem is.
What's that?
You're bored.
I think you're right.
Do you ever have falling dreams?
Sure. I think so.
I have the same dream all the time
where it's really high, I'm kinda floating,
and then I fall.
Is that the same as yours?
Kind of.
Well, why, what happens in yours?
I wake up before I hit the ground.
I always hit.
I don't wake up.
That's not normal.
I know.
I got a bad feeling.
About what?
Some strange shit's been going down.
Saad's up to something, and it's nothing good.
I keep thinking
about that stash that disappeared.
I mean, Parsons was stupid, but he wasn't crazy.
He wouldn't try to rip us off.
I'm going out to the storage room later,
check out that cabinet.
Maybe he put the stash in there wrong
and Saad couldn't find it.
OK.
Do you wanna kill Ray Elwood?
Jesus Christ, Robyn,
what are you talking about?
- Do you?
- What's he been saying?
Nothing.
I don't think you should be listening too much
to Ray fucking Elwood.
But you've killed people before
in war and stuff, right?
And now you wanna kill Ray Elwood.
It's no different, is it?
I really don't think
you know what you're talking about.
Holy shit, what happened to you?
Who the fuck did that to you?
Fuckers.
They're just stupid, stupid, stupid... fuckers.
Take it easy. Let me look at you.
Oh, fuck!
Hey. Come on. Calm down.
Just let me clean it up, all right?
I've got some stuff here.
Put this under your tongue and let it dissolve.
What is that?
It'll calm you down.
Oh, fuck.
Man, I told you. You can't walk
around this end of the base alone at night.
It just ain't safe.
Hey, you want a beer?
- I'll get you a beer, yeah?
- OK.
Thanks.
You know, a lot of guys
take a beating around here.
Just don't let it happen twice.
My daddy still keeps in touch
with his army buddies.
The guys he knew... from World War II.
You know,
they get together every year for a barbecue.
Friends for life, man.
Yeah.
I guess I've been kind of an asshole to you.
This place is fucked up.
It fucks with your head, and...
sometimes you don't know who to trust,
you know?
Yeah.
Well, I think tonight ended up OK.
Don't you think?
A stunning success. You should be very happy.
Liz,
why don't you put that down for a while?
Hm?
- Well, honey, it's been a while.
- Wallace.
- Who do you think you are?
- What do you mean?
When was the last time you even held a rifle?
Do you even know which end
the fucking bullets come out?
Why, in your opinion, was it a good idea
to challenge Marshall to a training exercise
when you're Supply and he's Infantry?
You told me I should go on the attack.
Right. I said attack.
I didn't say fall on your own sword.
Well, I had to do something, and...
And I'll tell you what.
I think I've got Marshall's number.
I know how he thinks,
I know his battle strategies.
I've been supplying him in Reforger,
for God's sake.
I'm confident I can show him up.
All I've got to do
is defend a nuke base for 48 hours.
Right?
The deal's off, sir.
I don't understand.
What do you mean, it's off?
There's just some bad shit happening right now
and I can't do it. I'm sorry.
The guns are already sold.
If you don't deliver, there's a big problem.
They killed one of my guys.
What did you expect?
Did you think this would be like a game?
A bit of fun?
I don't know.
Yeah.
Sit down, please.
Please sit down.
We got nothing left to talk about.
They killed your friend, huh?
Some fucking Russians killed my son.
You son of a bitch!
They tortured him and shot him in the head.
You talk to me about your friend?
I don't give a fuck about your friend.
The deal is still on.
Or I'll fucking kill you.
I'll come and find you and I'll fucking kill you.
OK?
Man?
- How did it go?
- Great. Just great.
How the fuck are we supposed to get the guns
out of the nuke base with this training exercise?
If Berman's exercise lasts all weekend,
there's no way we're gonna get the guns out.
- The only way is if the exercise finishes early.
- Yeah, man.
If we're not dead by 1700, we're fucking dead.
- I'll take care of it.
- How the fuck are you gonna take care of it?
I said I'll fucking take care of it.
Holy shit.
This place is closed for business, baby.
Get out. Let's go.
What you looking at, son?
You better get on out of here.
Move. Move it.
No, no, no. Not you, Elwood.
You have no authority here, Sergeant.
You can't just walk in here
and close this bar down.
- You have no right.
- You're a real bad motherfucker, ain't you?
Take him to the shed.
- Hey, get the fuck off me.
- Kick his fucking ass.
- Hey, get the fuck off, you bastards.
- Guys.
Fuck off me.
- What do you want?
- A little investment advice.
On what?
How much you think you'll make
on that shipment?
It'll tide me over.
Well, do you know what security on that'll be?
Well, I guess you're here
to give me a price quote.
You know, the thing I love about you, Elwood,
is that it don't take you long
to figure out the play.
Get the fuck out.
You stupid fuck. Fuck!
- Fuck. Get out, fuck!
- All right. Calm down.
Fuck.
Motherfucker.
Fuck him. Fuck him.
Stupid motherfucker.
Don't you learn?
Huh? Don't you fucking learn?
You wanna talk business, right?
So let's talk business.
OK.
Let's talk business.
You want a cut?
A cut? What the fuck
are you talking about, a cut?
I'm your brand-new fucking partner.
I think you might have saved my life back there.
Thanks. I owe you one.
You OK? They hurt you again?
No, I just kind of got a sore elbow.
- Listen, I need a favour.
- Yeah. Anything. Anything, man. What is it?
The thing about cooking smack is,
to not get fucked up by the fumes,
you gotta have a full stomach.
Cook smack on an empty stomach,
you'll be stoned as any junkie.
The problem we got now
is we're cooking ten times more than before.
So to stay awake,
we have to eat a burger like every 15 minutes.
- So, for six hours, like...
- That's 24 burgers. That's a lot of burgers.
Yeah.
They don't teach you about this stuff in basic.
So, look, I need you to do the shopping for me.
Go into the commissary here and get food.
Burgers, hotdogs - anything with meat.
Lots of meat.
Yeah, OK, no problem.
Catch my drift here, right?
Saad doesn't eat meat.
He's decided to hold back.
He won't come until tonight.
There's no way
he's gonna mount an attack in the day.
I think you may be right, sir.
I know I'm right, Elwood.
He wants to wait till we're worn down,
used up all our supplies, had false alerts.
Two trucks coming, sir.
Aha, breakfast!
We got fresh coffee, doughnuts,
hash browns, eggs, flapjacks.
- Garcia, let's get in there.
- Yes, sir.
- These two trucks, let them through.
Stop.
Why the hell did they go over there?
Go, go, go!
Move, move!
Drop your weapons. Move it!
Bang.
You're dead.
- Yeah!
- Yeah! Come on. Let's go.
Way to run it, way to run it, way to run it.
Nice play, nice play.
Here we go. Come on, come on. Line up.
OK, sir?
Did I ever tell you I met President Kennedy?
No.
He delivered the graduation address
at the academy.
You can't tell it from his pictures, but...
up close in person he...
he just had this charisma.
I shook the President's hand.
I felt his strength, and I thought...
I can do anything I set my mind to.
Do you know
what General Lancaster called me?
Incompetent.
Will he include that in your efficiency report, sir?
Oh, yeah. Yes, I'm sure he will.
The General has relieved me of my command.
Marshall said
his executive officer could take over.
I'm really sorry, sir.
You know what I'm gonna do, Elwood?
I'm gonna take my pension
and buy that vineyard.
I think that's what I'm going to do.
That doesn't sound like such a bad idea,
does it?
Make sure and give the Turk all my love.
Hey, you feel bad about Berman?
Oh, fuck, no.
You don't feel bad about tipping off Marshall?
I thought you liked Berman.
Way I see it, I did him a fucking favour.
Berman's too nice a guy for the army.
I know I did it to save my own ass, but...
he's gonna make fucking wine.
We're stuck here up to our necks in shit.
Why the delay? Couldn't find the base?
- You boys are looking tense.
- We're having a ball.
Let's get this stuff inside.
So, how long does it take to cook this stuff?
Most of the night.
What the fuck is he doing here?
He's with me. Got a problem with that?
Whoa, whoa, Saad,
do me a favour and put that out. Now.
I'm not fucking around.
This is highly flammable shit.
Now, listen up. We cook six hours and
we have to keep it as close as possible to 85oC.
What happens if it goes below?
If it goes below 80, the reaction stops,
we gotta cook longer.
If it goes above 90, the morphine's destroyed,
and if it boils, well...
Well, what?
Cooking smack is like
preparing Thanksgiving dinner
where one ingredient is a hand grenade.
This shit explodes?
- Kaboom.
- You better know what the fuck you're doing.
I just hope the ventilators can handle it.
This is way more than we've ever done before.
If we change the filter element every hour,
it should be OK. You on it?
I'm on it, man.
Saad, do you want a hotdog?
I don't want no fucking hotdog.
You got no vegetarian shit?
Hotdogs are made up
of lips, udders and assholes.
- I'm surprised you don't want one.
- I'll fuck you up.
Please, just fucking cut the sarcasm.
Can we just eat our hotdogs and chill out?
Not you, of course, Saad.
OK, six hours. Mark it now.
Knoll.
I'm gonna go get some rest.
I'll be back at 0400.
I'm leaving you in charge, buddy.
You leaving? Where are you going?
What are you worried about?
Just kick back,
watch some TV, educate yourself.
You own this base, right?
...all afternoon. It is clear that this will be
one of Berlin's most dramatic days.
Robyn?
Come on up.
I don't think so.
Just get up here.
Come on up. Come on.
Just a bit further.
- Jesus Christ, this is not fun.
- What's the matter? Are you scared?
Of course I'm not scared.
- I won't push you.
- Yeah, well, I'd appreciate that.
Come on, come on.
Come on. Come up to the edge.
Take another step.
Take another two steps.
Just a little bit further. Come on.
Sit down.
What would it take to make you jump?
A parachute.
Oh, fuck.
That's really high.
Maybe you get used to it after a while.
I think the point is not to get used to it.
What are you doing?
Why are you putting your arms up like that?
Robyn.
Oh.
Fuck it!
Robyn?
Hi.
...with growing German opposition
to the siting of nuclear missiles on their soil,
Brussels changed all that.
A relieved Chancellor Kohl could now offer
his electorate what they have been demanding.
The President seemed happy to celebrate...
I got you.
Mr President, we're glad you're here.
You are a friend amongst friends.
Why do you motherfuckers eat so damn much?
Because we're growing lads.
We need to keep our strength up.
Oh.
- I don't feel too good.
- Mm-hm.
Let me get one of those burgers.
No fucking way, Saad. This shit's like poison.
Wouldn't want you blocking up your arteries.
Fuck you.
Knoll. Shit, what time is it?
It's midnight.
What's going on?
Where you going?
- Fuck. I gotta go.
- Can I come?
They're in there.
Oh, fuck.
Leave him alone.
Stop it!
Sir, can I ask you to please take her out of here?
Sir?
What do you mean "sir"?
Let me go!
Your Second Lieutenant Brian Knoll
just got out of the Inspector General's office.
PFC Knoll, our officer in the hole.
Don't kick.
From the moment the first wave of East
Germans crossed into Berlin in the early hours...
Where is the Berlin Wall?
- It's in Berlin, you dumb fuck.
I know it's in Berlin.
What country is it in?
It's in Germany, man.
Fucking... Germany. West Germany.
West Germany?
Well, which one are we in, then?
Are we in West Germany
or are we in East Germany?
We're in East.
We're in West Germany, you idiot.
- What's the difference?
- Fucked if I know, man.
Get your fucking hands in the air,
you motherfuckers.
Get your fucking hands in the air.
Put it down. I'm warning you.
Drop that weapon.
You put your shit down, motherfucker.
This is my house.
Drop the fucking weapon.
No, fuck that.
Don't make another move.
You put your shit down. Fuck you.
Come on.
It's over.
It's all over.
What are you doing with Robyn?
Don't you worry about her.
She's got nothing to do with you any more.
Let me go, you fuck!
Kimborough, you read me?
Captain Kimborough, come in.
Er, we got some resistance,
but nothing we can't handle.
So, you've been putting it to my daughter
and you think that's making war?
War, you dumb fuck, is playing for keeps.
Somebody as stupid as you, Elwood,
deserves to go down.
Take out your muscle, you turn to shit.
No backup. Too easy.
What?
Well, who do you think took out Stoney?
You are fucking stupid.
He's gonna kill him.
Can you wait one second?
Listen to me. My dad is going to kill him.
- He's gonna do something bad.
- That's ridiculous.
Where's he taking him? What's he doing?
- He's taking him to the stockade.
- He's not! The stockade's the other way.
Can you please see
where he's taking him?
You wanna hear the secret of Vietnam?
The secret of Vietnam's simple. I loved it.
Goddamn turkey shoot.
Whole damn thing was nothing but fun.
I'm just being honest.
I fucking well loved it.
Everyone else would, too, if we had won.
I did all sorts of shit.
Everything you've been doing here and more.
Lots more.
And Berliners are proclaiming a new era...
Let go. Let go. Let go of me!
Hold it, Sergeant. Get away from the window.
What are you doing here, sir?
Get away from the window.
Or I will shoot you, Sergeant.
You're gonna shoot me?
You got the balls to do something like that?
Boiling point.
When there is peace,
the warlike man attacks himself.
That's Nietzsche,
and his point is that there really is no peace.
There's always some war
somewhere with someone.
And there are no winners or losers, either.
Just those that are still around
to fight another day.
A Purple Heart, and er...
No, what is it?
Defence Superior Service Medal, sir.
Gas explosion.
Well, that's what I read in the Stars And Stripes.
- They think it was a gas explosion?
- Yes, sir. That's what they think.
And this er, Robert Lee, the Sergeant
that got the posthumous Silver Star,
you knew him well, did you?
Yes, sir. His daughter's my sweetheart.
Is that right? I didn't know that.
How's she doing?
She's doing OK, sir.
She's at college studying politics.
Political science.
She has her semester break next month
and she's flying over to see me.
Well, I'll look forward to meeting her.
Are you sure you're OK standing?
If the leg starts getting weary,
you just cop a squat.
Oh, I'll be fine. Thanks, sir.
OK.
It really is healing quite nicely.
I think the tropical air's doing it some good.
So, you like it here in Hawaii?
- Yeah. I'm settling in.
- That's good. That's good.
Now, see what have we got here?
Oh, just some requisitions, sir.
1,000 gallons of Mop & Glo?
Do we really need that much?
Well, cleanliness is next to godliness.
Well, that's what I always say, sir.
Held Down
This is dedicated to all my folks
Diagnosed with a bad case
of that proper upbringin'
And never took the time to fall in line or follow
Or swallow the thoughts
Of the recognised committees
who lurk throughout ya cities
Ya hood, ya town, no matter which type
You're from the same type of people
trying to hold you down
Just because you tailor-made
for bigger and better things
Never missed a chance
to move ahead of things
And what does it bring?
I tell you for me, it brought jealousy
and back wounds from all the stabbing
Cats posin' as my fan
just to get to grabbin' what's mine
I'm livin' in times
where my daughters are found
Around kids who can't afford thinkin' caps
But always found drinkin' raps
and eatin' on beats
Claimin' laws of the streets
But who made the laws?
Everybody playin' rebel
with no sign of a cause
Well, I feel the world around me
I've found that others bring you down
just to be down
You've got to make up your mind
Where you wanna be
Where you wanna go with your life
With your life
I'm never singin' the blues
but findin' the clues that maintain
And I been blessed to reign supreme
Over nearly every dream I had
and I made it come true
I'm an imperfect man
and I'm holding the clue to perfection
It doesn't seem to matter what direction I look
I find people settin' traps
Tryin' to find the goal without havin' any maps
Even friends of mine
Jump on line just to become my adversary
They felt they were entitled to the dairy I made
They don't come and chill or behave
And they got toast ready to burn
Not learnin' to live
But they yearnin' to take what you earn
Well, I feel the world around me
I've found that others will bring you down
just to be down
You've got to make up your mind
Where you wanna be
And where you wanna go with your life
With your life
So quick to place blame
And deny the shame we bring upon ourselves
So many names held accountable
for my own account
When a large amount was weight
That I made a shape
When I climbed I found
It was hard to find others around
to point my fingers at
Which made me realise the truth
The biggest suppressor can be your own ego
Looking for an excuse to plant roots
In a field of self-sorrow
To sprout and follow the first thing you feel
Nourishes your hunger to be respected
It gets hectic
And when I'm watching the news
and my daughter walks in
And choose to ask
Why were all those people on the floor
sleepin' covered in red?
I told her that they were looking for God
but found religion instead
Well, I feel the world around me
I've found that others will bring you down
just to be down
You've got to make up your mind
Where you wanna be
And where you wanna be with your life
With your life
Where you wanna be now
Sometime
Sometime...
I need my space to live
Well, I feel the world around me
I've found that others will bring you down
Others bring you down to be down
You've got to make up your mind
where you wanna be
Where you wanna be
With your life
With your life, with your life
Text Fix
Björn